VINCENT OKOLO

VINCENTAOKOLO@OUTLOOK.COM • 07389190993 101 SAINT ANDREWS AVENUE • HORNCHURCH • LONDON • RM3 5EA

PROFILE

Marketing analyst with 7 years experience in Paid Search turned Software Engineer. Developed skills in HTML, CSS and JavaScript through self-learning, then React, Node.js, Python Frameworks, Docker, Git and Github in a 13-week Bootcamp and implemented these technologies in fullstack web app projects. Passionate about full stack development, learning new tech and looking to develop and utilise my skills in a professional context.

KEY SKILLS & PERSONAL VALUES

- Advanced Excel
- SQL (Basic)
- Search Ads 360
- Google Analytics
- Adobe Analytics (Omniture)
- Google Data Studio
- Amazon Marketing Services (AMS)
- Yahoo Gemini Advertisement

- Google Ads
- Google Ad Scripts
- Marin Bid Management
- Microsoft Office (Word & Powerpoint)
- Facebook Marketing/Nanigans
- Reporting

- Diplomatic
- Critical thinker
- Team player
- Committed to exceeding expectations and targets

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kindred Group PLC

PPC Manager

Apr 20 - May 22

- Account management of £200k+ monthly spend across Search and Youtube activity for the US market (New Jersey, Indiana and Pennsylvania)
- Restructured Casino and Sportsbook account contributing to a 58% QoQ (Q3 vs. Q2 2020) increase in 'New Depositing Players' (NDPs) across the state of Pennsylvania
- Collaborated with Creative and Commercial teams to implement a multi-product landing page test across Sportsbook activity, which contributed to a 7% increase in registration to click ratio

Havas Media (Ecselis) - Contract

Paid Performance Manager

April 19 - Mar 20

- Managing 30k+ spend across both domestic and international Brand Awareness and Retail focused campaigns
- Forecasting and development of media plans for short term promotional activity for Homebase
- Creation of automated reports to keep track of account spend and generation of monthly client insight reports
- Managing client comms and working in unison with biddable planners to deliver on client targets
- Delivering Excel training for new joiners, going over numerical functions, lookups and pivot tables and charts

American Express June 17 - April 19

Marketing Analyst (Paid Search)

- Presenting key insights and performance metrics against targets during quarterly, monthly and weekly calls
- Assigned tasks to analytics counterpart and monitored work for quality
- Account Management across US, German and Austrian markets, liaising with various internal and external stakeholders across a matrix environment
- Proposed and implemented a multivariate ad and landing page test for the aim of complimenting business ATL activity that led to a tripling in conversion rate by making use of age and device campaign segmentation

Seven Star Digital Nov 16 – June 17

Paid Media Manager

Management of 100k+ monthly spend over four key categories within the iGaming sector spanning over four geos

- Excel and Adwords Script manipulation to generate automated reports to provide insight into account and campaign level profitability and ROI
- Competitor analysis for the purposes of expanding keyword sets and developing new ad tests
- Managing relationships with Account Managers at both Google and Bing to extract the most value possible from campaigns

MVFGlobal June 15 - Oct 16

Paid Media Executive

- Management of a total of 15 international, as well as domestic, SEM campaigns that market B2B products such as Web design services and Franking Machines generating approximately £13,000 worth of GP on a weekly basis
- Daily usage of Excel including the use of pivot tables, Vlookups, filtering and more to sort and analyse large data sets for the purpose of optimising accounts and achieving increased ROI
- Competence with in-house technical platforms such as Abbey and Mars and querying internal Databases with SQL to pull customer details to align with campaign metrics
- Development of an Adwords script in Javascript to pause campaigns based on whether a predefined conversion cap had been exceeded.

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep 2013 - Feb 2014 Vodafone, Solihull - *Retail Advisor*

Feb 2012 - Mar 2013 Marks and Spencer, Shirley – Customer Assistant

Jan 2010 - Jun 2010 UEL, London - Library Assistant

QUALIFICATIONS

Futureproof May 2022 - August 2022

Full Stack Software Developer program

o Modules include: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, React, Redux, Docker, MongoDB, Postgres, Netlify, Heroku. Github

University of Birmingham

2011 - 2015

• BA (Hons) Philosophy with a year in Computer Science – Grade: 2:1

*Extra modules also taken: 'Employability and development skills' and 'Project Management'

Saint Francis Xavier Sixth Form College

2009 - 2011

A LEVEL: Philosophy and Ethics (A*), Economics (B), English Literature (B): 340 UCAS points

Saint Thomas the Apostle Sixth Form College

2004 - 2009

• GCSE: 10 A* - B's, including 8 at grade; Mathematics (A); English Lang & Lit (AA)

*Awarded a certificate in recognition of academic excellence

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

VINCENTAOKOLO@OUTLOOK.COM • 07389190993